Zoe Robertson

Cross-skilled Web Developer excelling at improving workflows and app architecture to produce efficient and reusable code. Possesses an analytical and creative perspective to find the best solution with the technical expertise to implement and document it. Consistently cuts project times in half, while improving reliability and teaching others how to do the same. All done while keeping everyone happy.

13301 Se 26th Street Vancouver, WA 98683 (971) 272-6777 zoe.robertson.m@gmail.com https://zoerobertson.io

EXPERIENCE

Alma Rethink SIS, Portland OR — Data Engineer

NOVEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

Triage and resolve front/back end production bugs on a distributed cloud application. Oversee 3rd party integrations and the data in/out requirements. Resolve data issues on production MongoDB servers. Analyze and import data from a wide variety of sources (SQL, txt, csv) utilizing PHP and JavaScript.

Alma Rethink SIS, Portland OR — Reporting Analyst

NOVEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018

Project manager and SME on highly complex State Department of Education data reporting. Research requirements then define business logic, file specifications and custom application fields to accurately report data. Work closely with account management and high ranking educational district administrators to resolve and diffuse reporting concerns.

Hewlett Packard Ink, Vancouver WA — Technician I

Under Pactera Technologies

FEBRUARY 2017 - NOVEMBER 2017

Q.A. Test prototype printing hardware. Meticulously document observations and errors. Supervise test operators and provide troubleshooting assistance. Write Powershell scripts to automate testing and improve productivity.

EDUCATION

Udacity, Online — Front End Web Developer Nanodegree

MAY 2018 - NOVEMBER 2018

Earned a full scholarship through Grow With Google & Udacity Challenge, awarded to 10% of applicants. Thorough project based instruction on contemporary Front End trends such as Progressive Web Apps, Responsive & Accessible Web Design and optimizing JavaScript.

SKILLS

Front End: HTML5, CSS3, CSS Preprocessors, JavaScript, React.js, Service Workers.

Back End: PHP 7, Node.js, Express.js, Gulp.js, MongoDB, SQL, Bash, Nginx.

Debugging & Other Tools:

Chrome Dev Tools, Unix Terminal, Vagrant, Git, Jira, Bitbucket.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Alma, Data Engineer:

Introduced & developed an application which reduced project time by 25% on first implementation, and reduced an 8 week project to 1 week on second implementation.

Alma, Reporting Analyst: In one year, added support for 5 new states from conception to completion, more than doubling the previous average of 2 new states annually.

HP Ink, Technician I:
Selected by site project
manager to work directly
under a mechanical engineer
for the client (HP) as the sole
representative on behalf of
Pactera Technologies.